[
  {
    "question": "Because of British influence, Bone Island is also known as the Island of",
    "a": "Death",
    "b": "Doom",
    "c": "Maggots",
    "d": "Vultures",
    "e": "Scavengers",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Gita offer free drinks to Angel and her family in Chapter 12 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "She has no other women for company.",
    "b": "She takes pity on them and their appearances.",
    "c": "She can afford to be generous because of the miners.",
    "d": "She is scheming to drug and rob them.",
    "e": "She plans to overcharge them for lodging.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "The miners at North House use all of the following methods to try to improve their luck EXCEPT",
    "a": "a Ouija board",
    "b": "a rabbit's foot",
    "c": "offering tobacco",
    "d": "prayers",
    "e": "atmospheric signs",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 12 of Solar Storms, John Husk mailed all of the following items with Agnes's coat EXCEPT a",
    "a": "book on astrology",
    "b": "chocolate bar",
    "c": "jar of lotion",
    "d": "fishing lure",
    "e": "can of salmon",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Chapter 12 of Solar Storms, why do the Sleepers reject electricity?",
    "a": "An elder told them it was an evil spirit.",
    "b": "As a Western invention, it earns their scorn.",
    "c": "Their previous village burned in an electric fire.",
    "d": "They believe it interfered with the aurora.",
    "e": "They believe that electricity should be free.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 12 of Solar Storms, Dora-Rouge calls their destination",
    "a": "Ilaba",
    "b": "Utu",
    "c": "Orago",
    "d": "Ezina",
    "e": "Ahani",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is Angel not present when Agnes dies?",
    "a": "She was sent fishing by Bush.",
    "b": "She fell sick herself with swamp fever.",
    "c": "She has run away in spite and frustration.",
    "d": "She is on a quest to gather healing herbs.",
    "e": "She went ahead to Two-Town for help.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Agnes dies, she is set adrift while covered with",
    "a": "green leaves",
    "b": "black earth",
    "c": "white petals",
    "d": "blue flowers",
    "e": "red roots",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Angel thinks Bush may have lied about the time of Agnes's death to",
    "a": "hide how long Agnes was ill",
    "b": "avoid ruining Angel's birthday",
    "c": "keep Angel from feeling guilt",
    "d": "encourage the party to speed up",
    "e": "cover up missing supplies",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chapter 13 of Solar Storms opens with Angel",
    "a": "burying Agnes's body near her ancestors",
    "b": "falling ill the way Agnes had",
    "c": "listening to the details of Dora-Rouge's deal",
    "d": "questioning the purpose of the journey",
    "e": "confronting a would-be thief",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dora-Rouge's deal with the water ruptures her relationship with",
    "a": "LaRue Marks Time",
    "b": "John Husk",
    "c": "Luther",
    "d": "Tommy Grove",
    "e": "Tulik",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Holy String Town received its name for its resemblance to a(n)",
    "a": "rosary",
    "b": "altar cloth",
    "c": "dreamcatcher",
    "d": "tefillah",
    "e": "rope belt",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is Angel upset about staying with Mrs. Lampier?",
    "a": "She doesn't have access to a toilet.",
    "b": "She hates the pictures on the wall.",
    "c": "She dislikes the time electricity cuts off.",
    "d": "She mistrusts Mrs. Lampier.",
    "e": "She wants a bed, not a cot.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 13 of Solar Storms, Jon steals all of the following items EXCEPT",
    "a": "sleeping bags",
    "b": "a canoe",
    "c": "beaver pelts",
    "d": "a tent",
    "e": "food",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chapter 14 of Solar Storms envisions construction work being destroyed by",
    "a": "Métis resistance groups",
    "b": "an earthquake",
    "c": "the Riel River",
    "d": "beavers",
    "e": "ice and snow",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Chapter 15 of Solar Storms, the youth in the area abuse alcohol and",
    "a": "inhalants",
    "b": "marijuana",
    "c": "heroin",
    "d": "crack cocaine",
    "e": "LSD",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following clothing brands does Angel mistake for a man’s name?",
    "a": "Montgomery Ward",
    "b": "R.H. Macy",
    "c": "Pierre Cardin",
    "d": "Tom Ford",
    "e": "Eddie Bauer",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 15 of Solar Storms, how does Angel lose a shoe?",
    "a": "It falls to the bottom of the lake.",
    "b": "A dog takes it while she is swimming.",
    "c": "A child steals it while she is showering.",
    "d": "Hannah holds it to make Angel talk to her.",
    "e": "It sinks into the mud after she slips.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Angel confronts her, how does Hannah try to evade responsibility for her abuse of Angel?",
    "a": "She uses exact words to imply false figurative meanings.",
    "b": "She says Angel brought the abuse upon herself.",
    "c": "She provokes Angel and uses her reaction as an excuse to leave.",
    "d": "She claims Bush was the actual abuser, not her.",
    "e": "She gives Angel the silent treatment, refusing to talk.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do the police use the pretext of the fire code to evict Angel’s family in Chapter 15 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "Dora-Rouge is attracting spiritual followers.",
    "b": "Hannah has been hanging around their house.",
    "c": "The family has not paid the bill for the search plane.",
    "d": "Angel is suspected of stealing a bicycle.",
    "e": "Bush has been speaking out regarding the dams.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Angel regret insisting to Tulik that she not sleep on a cot?",
    "a": "She has to stay outside in a sleeping bag.",
    "b": "She ends up sleeping on the floor.",
    "c": "Her family must find other accommodation.",
    "d": "The sleeping platform she uses instead has no privacy.",
    "e": "Tulik fixes up a tent in his yard just for her.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Tulik refuse to say “starvation” in his Indigenous language?",
    "a": "Auntie has vowed to leave him if he does.",
    "b": "Doing so could cause it to come back.",
    "c": "There is no exact translation in his language.",
    "d": "That is how his mother died.",
    "e": "The word has become an obscenity.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to reach Hannah’s house, Angel has to walk",
    "a": "two miles",
    "b": "five miles",
    "c": "four miles",
    "d": "three miles",
    "e": "one mile",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "The men who kept vigil at Hannah’s cabin bring Angel all of the following supplies EXCEPT",
    "a": "swamp tea",
    "b": "biscuits",
    "c": "coffee",
    "d": "powdered milk",
    "e": "stew",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 16 of Solar Storms, Hannah from",
    "a": "being stabbed",
    "b": "a drug overdose",
    "c": "being shot",
    "d": "a blood infection",
    "e": "liver disease",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did the nearest medicine man not try to heal Hannah at the end of her life?",
    "a": "He was too far away to travel.",
    "b": "He was scarred from his last try at helping her.",
    "c": "He was trying to raise an infant alone.",
    "d": "He was too inexperienced to handle her.",
    "e": "He was drunk and not fit for the rites.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did the legal system handle the brothers who killed a woman in 1936?",
    "a": "Vigilantes killed them before the trial.",
    "b": "They were freed on grounds of self-defense.",
    "c": "They were imprisoned after a jury trial.",
    "d": "The state failed to press charges.",
    "e": "They were executed on a judge’s orders.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Angel put Aurora outside while Hannah is dying?",
    "a": "She feels the outside air is warmer.",
    "b": "She leaves no witnesses to her revenge.",
    "c": "She keeps Hannah from trying to bite Aurora.",
    "d": "She wants Aurora safe from evil spirits.",
    "e": "She needs a space free from distractions.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In exchange for safe passage down the Se Nay River, Dora-Rouge knowingly traded away her",
    "a": "afterlife with Luther",
    "b": "guardianship of the corn",
    "c": "great-granddaughter Hannah",
    "d": "daughter Agnes",
    "e": "envisioned death",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At Two-Town Post, Bush trades beaver pelts for all of the following items EXCEPT",
    "a": "blue jeans",
    "b": "apples",
    "c": "sewing supplies",
    "d": "ham",
    "e": "money",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]